#### SINTAYEHU MEKONNEN

sintemite@gmail.com
https://sintu.ga
https://www.linkedin.com/in/sintayehu-mekonnen-35b88716a/
(404) 935-2192

# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

I have proven skills in web development including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I have extensive experience as a Web Developer who knows how to create, design, and modify web content. I am also well-trained in basic Computer Science.

I am an energetic, results-driven individual with the capacity to adapt and learn fast. I have excellent communication skills, time management and ability to multi-task and work in a fast-paced environment. I have a creative approach and passion for work. I am an outstanding and conscientious team player, who is willing to learn new skills. I possess a positive attitude and have experience working in diverse environments.

## **EDUCATION**

# Georgia Piedmont Technical College, Clarkston, GA

Associate Degree in Applied Science: Computer Support Specialist (2018) Help Desk Specialist Certificate (April 2018) PC Repair and Network Technician Certificate (July 2017) CompTIA A+ Certified Technician Preparation Certificate (Dec 2017)

# **Udemy**

Web Developer Bootcamp Certificate (March 2018) AngularJS Certificate (Nov 2017) Node JS Certificate (Nov 2017) Build a Real Time web app Certificate (Nov 2017)

#### Friends of Refugees

Web Development Certificate (August 2017)

## **Ethiopian Civil Service University**

Transformational Leadership Development and Decision-Making Certificate (December 2013)

#### **SKILLS**

- Web Development
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- iQuery

- Node.js
- Expres.js
- Frameworks
  - GitHub
- Git
- FTP

- Chrome Inspector
- Debugging tools
- Coding tools
- Web Hosting
- Cross-browser development
- Knowledge about computer hardware and software

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Web Developer and IT Consultant Clarkston, GA 2016 - present

- Experience in developing websites and applications using latest web technologies.
- Developed responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Sample: https://sintu.ga)
- Design, Develop, Review/Analyze, and modify programming systems including coding, testing, debugging and documenting programs.
- Utilized creative and analytical problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- Worked on Cross-Browser compatibility and fixed the bugs for several browsers.
- Installed and updated software with a package manager.
- Troubleshoot personal, family and friend's computers including networking peripheral devices

# Customer Service Rep/Cashier Dekalb Farmers Market – Decatur, GA 2015 –2017

- Exhibited professionalism and effective verbal and written communication skills to enhance customer experience
- Navigate file and folder structure, and created customer data
- Updated customer information in the customer service database
- Provided information on procedures or policies
- Calculated total payments received and reconciled this with total sales
- Performed quick math calculations when collecting payments

# Relation Officer and School Coordinator Communication Affairs and Education Office -

Ethiopia 2007 – 2015

- Maintained and updated information on the organization's website
- Documented 400 teachers and 34 school's data in the organization database
- Created and modified tables entered and maintained data in the database
- Coordinated, organized and managed several events of the office
- Identified, analyzed and solved problems of schools, teachers, and supervisors
- Developed personal and the organization annual plan.
- Assisted in the development of plans and reports of the office